Afzal Lakdawala

Technical Lead

Summary

Over 9.5+ years of IT experience in various projects. I've done everything from the most basic CSS to setting up production servers. I've worked with amazing teams. I like to get my hands dirty and learn as many different skills as possible. I'm passionate about clean code continuously improving skills.

Work experience

Technical Lead 2017 - Present

Indiavidual Learning PVT. LTD.

Indiavidual Learning is an exciting venture backed education-technology start-up based in Mumbai (Andheri) now Bangalore (Koramangala). We are working to individualize education in India starting with all massively competitive, really tough exams (JEE!) which invite insane spending and paranoia. We want to make the path to these tests exciting, collaborative and open. We have a brilliant, open culture and believe in empowerment and an idea led hierarchy.

Some of the best investors and mentors in the country are aligned to our success and continue to help us shape the road to creating an exemplary product and people company in India.

Senior Software Engineer

2015 - 2017

Indiavidual Learning PVT. LTD.

Indiavidual Learning is an exciting venture backed education-technology start-up based in Mumbai (Andheri) now Bangalore (Koramangala). We are working to individualize education in India starting with all massively competitive, really tough exams (JEE!) which invite insane spending and paranoia. We want to make the path to these tests exciting, collaborative and open. We have a brilliant, open culture and believe in empowerment and an idea led hierarchy.

Some of the best investors and mentors in the country are aligned to our success and continue to help us shape the road to creating an exemplary product and people company in India.

Web Engineer 2013 - 2015

Pykih Software LLP

Pykih is a Mumbai-based data design company, that builds intuitive web-based experiences for discovering and communicating insights hidden in data. Pykih's data visualisations have helped global companies like Microsoft, Visually, DataWrapper, 23AndMe, Microsoft, ICICI Lombard, NarendraModi.in and Oxfam India amongst others.

Co-Founder 2012 - 2013

Affire Techlab

Started as product based company, provides a platform to publishers where they can get connected to thousands of others publishers and exchange their traffic to help each other to grow that too free of cost.

Application and Web Developer

2008 - 2012

Raj Computers

Rapidly growing software company with a team of experienced intellectuals working in various technologies. It deals with Product and Service based applications. Committed to the qualitative, efficiency, innovativeness and timeliness of deliverables with high focus on maximum customer satisfaction.

Portfolio

1. Raj Computers

- Bus Management This software is been developed with the help of bus operators whose having their own buses, which they give on hire or runs by own.
- Stock Inventory Software is equipped with a low-level warning system that will alert you when your stock is getting low so you don't run out of something that is selling well. You also have the ability to see in real time what stock you have on hand at another location and keep track of it. If you offer item kits it's important to use a program that will allow you to keep an eye on your sales and inventory so that your kits are all accounted for. Inventory Software can provide you with the advanced functionality you require enabling you to regain control of your profits.
- Builder and Development System has been designed to ensure a faster, more accurate and streamlined flow of information between clients, residential builders, suppliers and traders. This leads to a significant reduction in paperwork and allows more time to be spent on the actual construction process and less on administration tasks. The time savings and flow on effects ensure a quick and positive return on investment. Software allows your staff to spend more time on task and on site.
- Hotel Management Includes all the features required in a Hotel such as reservation reception
 (Front Office), accounts, Hotel Point of Sales (Restaurant, Bar, Room Service, House Keeping or any
 other outlet). It emphasizes the highest level of individual guest services through our comprehensive
 features seamlessly integrating rooms, dining, and retail, with information contained in reservations
 till back office general ledger.

2. Pykih Software LLP

- NarendraModi.in uses a pykih viz. on his homepage for over a month.
- Builds visuals for FirstPost.com (Network 18) cricket, elections and budget.
- Builds a live Social Wall for Microsoft's World Partner Conference.
- Helps Europeana launch an Open Statistics Site that lists performance of 5+ million digital assets, contributed by 150 museums and libraries across 39 European countries.
- Pykih's cricket scorecard is featured in a History Channel Documentary.

3. Affire TechLab

- adshub Provides a platform to publishers where they can get connected to thousands of others publishers and exchange their traffic to help each other to grow that too free of cost.
- killerjeans Backend and store locator

4. Indiavidual Learning PVT LTD.

 Complete css to production deployment product building. Content migration, script automation, Scaling of app, R&D, Security, Risk factors, Optimisations (queries and page load time).
 Been part of core tech over a couple of years and now take it to the new level altogether.
 My vision for Embibe as the product is to take the product and make sure it is available to each and every new generation of student.

For e-commerce we have Flipkart and for ticketing we have Goibibo, I want Embibe which stand as a brand for education technology.

Making a user-friendly App and convenient to use and tech wise scalable, lightweight yet simple for students.

Skills Server-Side Languages Ruby (Ruby on Rails), PHP (Codelgniter) Front End Javascript/jQuery, Bootstrap, CSS, HAML/ERB/SLIM, HTML, AngularJs, D3|s, Underscore|s, React|s, ReactNative **Databases** PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB Caching Redis, Memcached. **Analytics and System** Elasticsearch, Google Analytics, Segmentio, Intercom Monitoring Cloud AWS (EC2, RDS, S3, CloudFront, etc.), Digital Ocean, Rackspace, Hostgator, Godaddy. Transactional Email, Email Mandrill API, MailChimp Marketing

Github, Bitbucket

Razorpay, CCavenue, Paypal, 2checkout.

Education

Sir j.j fort boys high school

Mumbai, Maharashtra

Version Control

Payment Gateway

Burhani college of commerce and arts

Mumbai, Maharashtra

Diploma in electrical engineering

Mumbai, Maharashtra